Kevin Keegan Dublin, Ireland

www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-keegan-engineer

kevinkeegans@gmail.com +353-876428470

SUMMARY

Electronic Engineer with 2 years of industry experience.

1st Class Honours Masters degree in Electronic & Computer Engineering from University College Dublin.

Experienced in Verilog, Python, C, Java, MATLAB & Linux.

Interested primarily in digital signal processing, digital ASIC design and embedded systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages/Tools: Verilog, Python, Bash, Java, C/C++, LISP, ASM (MIPS32, 8051), MATLAB, Git, IATEX.
- Network Programming: Experienced in TCP/IP Socket programming in Python, C & Java.
- Concurrent Programming: Experience in multiprocessing & multi-threaded development.
- Operating Systems: Professional experience developing in Linux and Windows environments.
- Embedded Systems: Experience in front-end Digital Design (RTL) & developing for microcontrollers such as Arduino, Micropython & ADuC841. Knowledgeable in the use of Hardware Timers/Counters, Interrupt service routines and SPI communication.
- Digital Signal Processing: Knowledgeable in Fourier analysis, digital filtering and digital communication theory.

Professional Experience

Adesto, ASIC & IP Division

Dublin, Ireland

Jan 2020 - Present

- Mixed Signal Design Engineer
 - o Front-End Digital Design
 - Developed software to automatically generate a Verilog implementation of a frequently redesigned block, along with its System Verilog testbench.

Susquehanna International Group (SIG)

Dublin, Ireland

Market Data Engineer

Sept 2018 - Nov 2019

- o Monitoring and maintaining critical market data systems.
- o Pcap file analysis via Wireshark/tshark
- $\circ~$ Developed validation tools to test new software before pushing to production.
- Implemented a system in Python & Bash to archive daily market data recordings from company colocations to a central archive.
- Developed a set of scripts to analyse the latency of a market data system when subject to a high data rates.
- o On call work. When on call, I was the first point of contact for issues regarding SIG's market data infrastructure.

Intel Corporation, Internet of Things and Wearables Group

Kildare, Ireland

Physical Design Engineer Intern

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

• Worked in a team designing a system in TCL to automate the design, layout & routing of a custom CMOS block.

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

 $Voluntary\ Teaching\ Assistant$

Sept 2015 - Nov 2015

• Voluntary Teaching Assistant in weekly laboratories for the engineering module, EEEN20010 Computer Engineering I: Data Structures and Algorithms through C.

FireEye, Inc.

Dublin, Ireland

May 2015 - July 2015

- Software Engineer Intern
 - Developed BASH scripts to facilitate and automate product testing.
 - Built a customized, kickstarted centOS distro to include the configurations and packages necessary for running & testing a company product.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Master of Engineering in Electronic & Computer Engineering; 1st Class Honours

Sept 2016 - Sept 2018

o **GPA**: 3.84/4.2

• UCD Intel Masters Scholarship: Awarded by Intel to top five students entering ME program.

University of California Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

Exchange - Electrical & Electronic Engineering; GPA: 3.18/4.0

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Bachelor of Science in Electrical & Electronic Engineering; 1st Class Honours

Sept 2013 - Sept 2016

GPA: 4.09/4.2

• Entrance Scholar: Awarded to top academic achievers entering UCD from secondary school.

Coláiste Eoin

E Eoin Dublin, Ireland

Irish Leaving Certificate; Points: 595

Sept 2007 - Jun 2013

PROJECTS

UCD Masters Research Project

Dublin, Ireland

Digital and Analog Implementations of Visible Light Communication

Sep 2017 - May 2018

- Project Thesis: thekegman.github.io/Thesis.pdf
- \circ My project proposes a real-time digital, visible light communication system employing a form of On-Off Keying modulation. It is implemented using an Arduino UNO based LED-Photodiode communication link. It can successfully transfer files between computers over a distance of up to 1.8m.
- Software for this system was developed in C & Python 3.

Custom Guitar Tuner

Analog amplifier & DSP running on pyboard

Jan 2020

- Designed an Op-amp based electric guitar amplifier, implemented on a breadboard.
- This amplified signal is sampled using a pyboard microcontroller.
- The pyboard runs an auto-correlation based pitch estimation algorithm I developed.
- This algorithm estimates the fundamental frequency of the string being played.
- LEDs are used to indicate if the string is in-tune, flat or sharp.

Noodle Dance Camera Filter

Python Script Jan 2020

- Python script using primarily numpy to recreate the popular Camera filter on TikTok.
- Source: github.com/Thekegman/noodledance

Spotify Collab Queue

WebApp Feb 2019

- Web app with a backend implemented in Python using the Flask framework.
- Using Spotify's API, this web app allows people to collaborate in what music is played by having them submit songs to a live queue.
- Source: github.com/Thekegman/spotify-collab-queue

Nikon Trigger

 $Microcontroller\ project$

Jan 2018

- $\circ~$ Program implemented for pyboard that uses an IR LED to remotely trigger a Nikon camera's shutter release.
- The 38kHz NEC protocol used by the Nikon 'ML-L3" camera remote is replicated using PWM hardware available on pyboard.
- Source: github.com/Thekegman/Nikon-Trigger-for-MicroPython

Android Apps

Implemented in Java, available on Google Play

- o Guess That Word May 2016
- The Maze Extravaganza 3D OpenGl Aug 2013
- The Maze Extravaganza 36k+ downloads July 2012
- o Developer page: http://tiny.cc/x32oaz